<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rayes</title>
    <link>https://rayes0.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on rayes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 12:03:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rayes0.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning (unfinished)</title>
      <link>https://rayes0.github.io/notes/machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 12:03:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rayes0.github.io/notes/machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>Some mathematical concepts and derivations that form the basis behind some simple machine learning algorithms. It can be viewed as a high level summary of Andrew Ng&amp;rsquo;s famous Coursera course, or any introductory machine learning textbook.
Helpful Prior Knowledge
 Basic linear algebra, fundamental operations ( \(&amp;#43;, -, \times, /\)    ) with vectors and matrices, transpose and inverse Basic conceptual calculus, taking derivatives  Basic Concepts  Features: The numerical inputs for the algorithm from which it makes predictions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finished</title>
      <link>https://rayes0.github.io/media/finished/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rayes0.github.io/media/finished/</guid>
      <description>Thoughts, opinions, reviews, and summaries on things I&amp;rsquo;ve finished since August 2021.
Books Fiction The Handmaid&amp;rsquo;s Tale, Margaret Atwood 08/04/21
 There is more than one kind of freedom,&amp;quot; said Aunt Lydia. &amp;ldquo;Freedom to and freedom from. In the days of anarchy, it was freedom to. Now you are being given freedom from. Don&amp;rsquo;t underrate it.&amp;rdquo;
The Handmaid&amp;rsquo;s Tale (Margaret Atwood)
 A very multifaceted novel full of symbolism and allusions that managed to somehow confuse, entertain, amaze me all at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Progress</title>
      <link>https://rayes0.github.io/media/in-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rayes0.github.io/media/in-progress/</guid>
      <description>Tracker for what I&#39;m currently reading/watching. Books   The Testaments, Margaret Atwood  Light Novels    Toradora [5/9]
  Progress   Vol 1 Vol 2 Vol 3 Vol 4 Vol 5 Vol 6 Vol 7 Vol 8 Vol 9     Manga    Shingeki no Kyojin [20/34]
  Progress   Vol. 1 Vol. 2 Vol. 3 Vol. 4 Vol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meta</title>
      <link>https://rayes0.github.io/meta/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rayes0.github.io/meta/</guid>
      <description>Meta page of various links to other content on this site.
Media A collection of things I have read/watched since August 2021. They are generated from my personal media org file with ox-hugo.
  In progress
  Finished
 Books Manga Anime    Other anemoia webnovel (not currently updating, see here)
Notes  Basics of Machine Learning (unfinished)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Artificial Consciousness *could be* Possible</title>
      <link>https://rayes0.github.io/blog/consiousness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 12:08:23 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rayes0.github.io/blog/consiousness/</guid>
      <description>It is commonly accepted that machines are not and cannot be conscious, and that any perceived consciousness is merely an imitation of organic consciousness. While I don&amp;rsquo;t disagree with these claims, there is not much solid proof for them, though of course, the same is true for the converse. However, it is still worth considering both sides of the problem. Therefore, for arguments sake, this article will lay out a series of examples and thought experiments potentially proving that artificial conscious could be possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://rayes0.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rayes0.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello, thanks for taking interest into my blog. This page contains some information about me and this site. It&amp;rsquo;s fairly long-winded for a simple about page, so read or skim it as you wish.
Me I typically go by the name rayes online. It&amp;rsquo;s not my actual name, just a pseudonym. I&amp;rsquo;m a 17 year old FOSS supporter, linux enthusiast, musician, and writer. I am fascinated by memory, the brain, and biology, especially relating to biochemistry, neuroscience and psychology, and machine learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychoanalysis of &#39;Slow Cold Chick&#39;</title>
      <link>https://rayes0.github.io/blog/slow-cold-chick/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 09:56:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rayes0.github.io/blog/slow-cold-chick/</guid>
      <description>ⓘ Note   This was a term paper originally written for my high school English course. I was proud how it turned out, so I decided to refactor some paragraphs and add headings, and republished it here.    Abstract Psychoanalysis, or at least the traditional version proposed by Sigmund Freud, is viewed by many modern psychologists as a highly controversial, sexist “pseudoscience” (1). There are many reasons for this, including dubious, untestable ideas, unethicality of some of the claims, and lack of scientific support, all of which are quite justified (2).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speculations on *Hyouka*</title>
      <link>https://rayes0.github.io/blog/hyouka/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 16:45:09 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rayes0.github.io/blog/hyouka/</guid>
      <description>The Classic Literature Club light novel series by Honobu Yonezawa showcases Oreki Houtarou, a high school boy and zealous energy conservationist. Starting with his first day of high school, the series follows him as he experiences new situations challenging his previous way of life. In this post, I want to share some thoughts about Hotarou and about his persona, which seems fairly common among individuals today, especially teens around Hotarou&amp;rsquo;s age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3</title>
      <link>https://rayes0.github.io/anemoia/chapter3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 21:49:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rayes0.github.io/anemoia/chapter3/</guid>
      <description>Evan rubbed his eyes. He was feeling slightly sleepy. It would probably be best to take a caffeine pill before he started his mission. Right now, Evan was in his dorm room. His roommate Philip seemed to have other things to do today. Maybe also an urgent mission? Evan didn&amp;rsquo;t know.
A few papers were propped up against his pillow. Next to them was a black file with the words &amp;lsquo;Grade A&amp;rsquo; written on the label.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2</title>
      <link>https://rayes0.github.io/anemoia/chapter2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 21:33:06 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rayes0.github.io/anemoia/chapter2/</guid>
      <description>There in the corner, encircled by shadows, was Headmaster Jules. He was a controlled man, who gave you the feeling that he was imperturbable. A former student at the school who, back in his day, was widely touted as the ideal version of a soldier. He was also rumoured to have been Nick&amp;rsquo;s teacher in his black suit days, and considered to have mastered the field of inferno magic. In other words, he was the best of the best.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1</title>
      <link>https://rayes0.github.io/anemoia/chapter1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 15:03:40 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rayes0.github.io/anemoia/chapter1/</guid>
      <description>(Twelve years after Prologue)
Evan awoke in his dorm room. He tried to open his eyes, but the morning sun filtering through the window was too much for him right now. Half squinting, he hauled himself out of the bed and proceeded to change into his blue suit. The dorms were nice and quiet at this time. Evan peered at another bed beside his, where his roommate Philip still lay sound asleep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prologue</title>
      <link>https://rayes0.github.io/anemoia/prologue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 21:42:35 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rayes0.github.io/anemoia/prologue/</guid>
      <description>It was a calm October day. The leaves were beginning to yellow. The air was damp but still clear, with a slight scent of morning dew still lingering. An open window let a constant, gentle breeze into the room, almost begging one to sit and daydream the day away. Time seemed to move in slow motion, like the lingering second before the last note of a beautiful piece of music.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
