<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>rayes</title><link>https://rayes0.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on rayes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-ca</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 14:40:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rayes0.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Modern Asian Pop Music Observations</title><link>https://rayes0.github.io/notes/anime-pop/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 14:40:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rayes0.github.io/notes/anime-pop/</guid><description>Some aggregated observations of common harmonic tendencies and chord progressions that give the modernistic Asian pop sound found in a lot of contemporary music from the East Asia region, in particular focusing on anime and film music. Some good examples of this type of sound include the music of film composers like Hayao Miyazaki, Joe Hisaishi, and Ryuichi Sakamoto, almost every anime opening or ending, some J-pop and C-pop artists, in particular mandopop artists like Jay Chou, Mayday, JJ Lin, contemporary Asian instrumental music (Yiruma in particular), and Western artists that also use this sound (Porter Robinson, even contemporary or neoclassical artists like Ludovico Einaudi and Maurice Ravel in certain sections of their music).</description></item><item><title>Tea Journal</title><link>https://rayes0.github.io/tea/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rayes0.github.io/tea/</guid><description>Collection of thoughts, notes, and reviews of loose-leaf tea and other water infused beverages that I&amp;rsquo;ve tried, including experimentation on custom blends with herbs, flowers, spices, berries, steeping methods, and roasting. Maybe some content about similar beverages like coffee as well (though I prefer tea to coffee). For each tea, I try to provide a photo of the label (if present) which typically contains important specs such as where the tea was grown and various related notes (they&amp;rsquo;ll mostly be in Chinese though).</description></item><item><title>Machine Learning</title><link>https://rayes0.github.io/notes/machine-learning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 12:03:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rayes0.github.io/notes/machine-learning/</guid><description>Some mathematical concepts and derivations that form the basis behind some simple machine learning algorithms. It can be viewed as a high level summary of Andrew Ng&amp;rsquo;s famous Coursera course, or any introductory machine learning textbook.
Helpful Prior Knowledge
Basic linear algebra, fundamental operations () with vectors and matrices, transpose and inverse Basic conceptual calculus, taking derivatives Basic Concepts Features: The numerical inputs for the algorithm from which it makes predictions.</description></item><item><title>A Search for the Best Spaced Learning Algorithm</title><link>https://rayes0.github.io/blog/spaced-repetition/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rayes0.github.io/blog/spaced-repetition/</guid><description>Spaced repetition is an evidence-based learning technique which utilizes the spacing effect. In contrast to more traditional repetition-based learning strategies such as cramming in which the main focus is on the total number of repetitions, spaced repetition is timing-based and focuses on maximizing efficiency by doing repetitions at scheduled times (typically decided by the difficulty of the material). Numerous studies have been conducted on spaced repetition (and on memory in general), and there is strong evidence suggesting that spaced repetition decreases the number of needed repetitions, and improves retention significantly over the long term.</description></item><item><title>Media</title><link>https://rayes0.github.io/media/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rayes0.github.io/media/</guid><description>Thoughts, opinions, reviews, and summaries on things I've finished since August 2021. May contain spoilers. Books Fiction The Handmaid&amp;rsquo;s Tale, Margaret Atwood 08/04/21
There is more than one kind of freedom,&amp;quot; said Aunt Lydia. &amp;ldquo;Freedom to and freedom from. In the days of anarchy, it was freedom to. Now you are being given freedom from. Don&amp;rsquo;t underrate it.&amp;rdquo;
The Handmaid&amp;rsquo;s Tale (Margaret Atwood)
A very multifaceted novel full of symbolism and allusions that managed to somehow confuse, entertain, amaze me all at the same time.</description></item><item><title>Why Artificial Consciousness may be possible</title><link>https://rayes0.github.io/blog/consciousness/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rayes0.github.io/blog/consciousness/</guid><description>It is commonly accepted that machines cannot be conscious, and that any perceived consciousness is merely an imitation of organic consciousness. While I don&amp;rsquo;t disagree with these claims, there is not much solid proof for them, though of course, the same is true for the converse. However, for various reasons, it is still worth considering both sides of the problem. Therefore, for arguments sake, this article will lay out a series of examples and thought experiments potentially showing that artificial conscious could be possible.</description></item><item><title>Meta</title><link>https://rayes0.github.io/meta/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rayes0.github.io/meta/</guid><description>Meta page of various links to other content on this site.
Media A collection of books and shows I have finished reading/watching since the file creation date (August 2021). They are generated from my personal media Org mode file.
Media Books Manga Anime Notes Dump of unfinished and unmaintained rough notes. Don&amp;rsquo;t expect accuracy, good grammar, or complete thoughts.
Basics of Machine Learning Anime Pop Analysis Other Tea journal anemoia webnovel (not currently updating, see here) Feeds A list of RSS and Atom feeds I am subscribed to.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://rayes0.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rayes0.github.io/about/</guid><description>Me I typically go by the name rayes online. It&amp;rsquo;s not my actual name, just a pseudonym. I&amp;rsquo;m a FOSS supporter, Linux enthusiast, musician, and writer. I am fascinated particularly by the brain, memory, neurobiology, and psychology.
Hobbies I have a fair amount of hobbies that I try to consistently do. They are fairly niche and a lot of them are uncommon, but I enjoy spending time on them, otherwise I would have dropped them already.</description></item><item><title>Psychoanalysis of 'Slow Cold Chick'</title><link>https://rayes0.github.io/blog/slow-cold-chick/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 09:56:01 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://rayes0.github.io/blog/slow-cold-chick/</guid><description>ⓘ Note This was a term paper originally written for my high school English course. I was fairly pleased with how it turned out, so I decided to refactor some paragraphs and add headings, and republish it here. Abstract Psychoanalysis, or at least the traditional version proposed by Sigmund Freud, is viewed by many modern psychologists as a highly controversial, sexist &amp;ldquo;pseudoscience&amp;rdquo; (1). There are many reasons for this, including dubious, untestable ideas, unethicality of some of the claims, and lack of scientific support, all of which are quite justified (2).</description></item><item><title>*Hyouka*: My Thoughts</title><link>https://rayes0.github.io/blog/hyouka/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 16:45:09 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://rayes0.github.io/blog/hyouka/</guid><description>Meta-collection of loosely chronologically ordered miscellaneous thoughts on the Classic Literature Club light novel series by Honobu Yonezawa, compiled slowly bit by bit over many weeks as I reread all 6 volumes and rewatch all 22 episodes. The series showcases Oreki Houtarou, a high school boy and zealous energy conservationist. Starting with his first day of high school, it follows him as he experiences new situations challenging his previous way of life.</description></item><item><title>Chapter 3</title><link>https://rayes0.github.io/anemoia/chapter3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 21:49:34 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://rayes0.github.io/anemoia/chapter3/</guid><description>Evan rubbed his eyes. He was feeling slightly sleepy. It would probably be best to take a caffeine pill before he started his mission. Right now, Evan was in his dorm room. His roommate Philip seemed to have other things to do today. Maybe also an urgent mission? Evan didn&amp;rsquo;t know.
A few papers were propped up against his pillow. Next to them was a black file with the words &amp;lsquo;Grade A&amp;rsquo; written on the label.</description></item><item><title>Chapter 2</title><link>https://rayes0.github.io/anemoia/chapter2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 21:33:06 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://rayes0.github.io/anemoia/chapter2/</guid><description>There in the corner, encircled by shadows, was Headmaster Jules. He was a controlled man, who gave you the feeling that he was imperturbable. A former student at the school who, back in his day, was widely touted as the ideal version of a soldier. He was also rumoured to have been Nick&amp;rsquo;s teacher in his black suit days, and considered to have mastered the field of inferno magic. In other words, he was the best of the best.</description></item><item><title>Chapter 1</title><link>https://rayes0.github.io/anemoia/chapter1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 15:03:40 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://rayes0.github.io/anemoia/chapter1/</guid><description>(Twelve years after Prologue)
Evan awoke in his dorm room. He tried to open his eyes, but the morning sun filtering through the window was too much for him right now. Half squinting, he hauled himself out of the bed and proceeded to change into his blue suit. The dorms were nice and quiet at this time. Evan peered at another bed beside his, where his roommate Philip still lay sound asleep.</description></item><item><title>Prologue</title><link>https://rayes0.github.io/anemoia/prologue/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 21:42:35 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://rayes0.github.io/anemoia/prologue/</guid><description>It was a calm October day. The leaves were beginning to yellow. The air was damp but still clear, with a slight scent of morning dew still lingering. An open window let a constant, gentle breeze into the room, almost begging one to sit and daydream the day away. Time seemed to move in slow motion, like the lingering second before the last note of a beautiful piece of music.</description></item></channel></rss>