<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>intelligence on rayes</title><link>https://rayes0.github.io/tags/intelligence/</link><description>Recent content in intelligence on rayes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-ca</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rayes0.github.io/tags/intelligence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Search for the Best Spaced Learning Algorithm</title><link>https://rayes0.github.io/blog/spaced-repetition/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rayes0.github.io/blog/spaced-repetition/</guid><description>Spaced repetition is an evidence-based learning technique which utilizes the spacing effect. In contrast to more traditional repetition-based learning strategies such as cramming in which the main focus is on the total number of repetitions, spaced repetition is timing-based and focuses on maximizing efficiency by doing repetitions at scheduled times (typically decided by the difficulty of the material). Numerous studies have been conducted on spaced repetition (and on memory in general), and there is strong evidence suggesting that spaced repetition decreases the number of needed repetitions, and improves retention significantly over the long term.</description></item><item><title>Why Artificial Consciousness may be possible</title><link>https://rayes0.github.io/blog/consciousness/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://rayes0.github.io/blog/consciousness/</guid><description>It is commonly accepted that machines cannot be conscious, and that any perceived consciousness is merely an imitation of organic consciousness. While I don&amp;rsquo;t disagree with these claims, there is not much solid proof for them, though of course, the same is true for the converse. However, it is still worth considering both sides of the problem. Therefore, for arguments sake, this article will lay out a series of examples and thought experiments potentially showing that artificial conscious could be possible.</description></item></channel></rss>