<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on rayes</title>
    <link>https://rayes0.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on rayes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language><atom:link href="https://rayes0.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Artificial Consciousness *could be* Possible</title>
      <link>https://rayes0.github.io/blog/consiousness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 12:08:23 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rayes0.github.io/blog/consiousness/</guid>
      <description>It is commonly accepted that machines are not and cannot be conscious, and that any perceived consciousness is merely an imitation of organic consciousness. While I don&amp;rsquo;t disagree with these claims, there is not much solid proof for them, though of course, the same is true for the converse. However, it is still worth considering both sides of the problem. Therefore, for arguments sake, this article will lay out a series of examples and thought experiments potentially proving that artificial conscious could be possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychoanalysis of &#39;Slow Cold Chick&#39;</title>
      <link>https://rayes0.github.io/blog/slow-cold-chick/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 09:56:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rayes0.github.io/blog/slow-cold-chick/</guid>
      <description>ⓘ Note   This was a term paper originally written for my high school English course. I was proud how it turned out, so I decided to refactor some paragraphs and add headings, and republished it here.    Abstract Psychoanalysis, or at least the traditional version proposed by Sigmund Freud, is viewed by many modern psychologists as a highly controversial, sexist “pseudoscience” (1). There are many reasons for this, including dubious, untestable ideas, unethicality of some of the claims, and lack of scientific support, all of which are quite justified (2).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speculations on *Hyouka*</title>
      <link>https://rayes0.github.io/blog/hyouka/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 16:45:09 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rayes0.github.io/blog/hyouka/</guid>
      <description>The Classic Literature Club light novel series by Honobu Yonezawa showcases Oreki Houtarou, a high school boy and zealous energy conservationist. Starting with his first day of high school, the series follows him as he experiences new situations challenging his previous way of life. In this post, I want to share some thoughts about Hotarou and about his persona, which seems fairly common among individuals today, especially teens around Hotarou&amp;rsquo;s age.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
