<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notes on rayes</title><link>https://rayes0.github.io/notes/</link><description>Recent content in Notes on rayes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-ca</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 14:40:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rayes0.github.io/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Modern Asian Pop Music Observations</title><link>https://rayes0.github.io/notes/anime-pop/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 14:40:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rayes0.github.io/notes/anime-pop/</guid><description>Some aggregated observations of common harmonic tendencies and chord progressions that give the modernistic Asian pop sound found in a lot of contemporary music from the East Asia region, in particular focusing on anime and film music. Some good examples of this type of sound include the music of film composers like Hayao Miyazaki, Joe Hisaishi, and Ryuichi Sakamoto, almost every anime opening or ending, some J-pop and C-pop artists, in particular mandopop artists like Jay Chou, Mayday, JJ Lin, contemporary Asian instrumental music (Yiruma in particular), and Western artists that also use this sound (Porter Robinson, even contemporary or neoclassical artists like Ludovico Einaudi and Maurice Ravel in certain sections of their music).</description></item><item><title>Machine Learning</title><link>https://rayes0.github.io/notes/machine-learning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 12:03:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rayes0.github.io/notes/machine-learning/</guid><description>Some mathematical concepts and derivations that form the basis behind some simple machine learning algorithms. It can be viewed as a high level summary of Andrew Ng&amp;rsquo;s famous Coursera course, or any introductory machine learning textbook.
Helpful Prior Knowledge
Basic linear algebra, fundamental operations () with vectors and matrices, transpose and inverse Basic conceptual calculus, taking derivatives Basic Concepts Features: The numerical inputs for the algorithm from which it makes predictions.</description></item></channel></rss>