<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>psychology on rayes</title><link>https://rayes0.github.io/tags/psychology/</link><description>Recent content in psychology on rayes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-ca</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 09:56:01 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rayes0.github.io/tags/psychology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Psychoanalysis of 'Slow Cold Chick'</title><link>https://rayes0.github.io/blog/slow-cold-chick/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 09:56:01 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://rayes0.github.io/blog/slow-cold-chick/</guid><description>ⓘ Note This was a term paper originally written for my high school English course. I was fairly pleased with how it turned out, so I decided to refactor some paragraphs and add headings, and republish it here. Abstract Psychoanalysis, or at least the traditional version proposed by Sigmund Freud, is viewed by many modern psychologists as a highly controversial, sexist &amp;ldquo;pseudoscience&amp;rdquo; (1). There are many reasons for this, including dubious, untestable ideas, unethicality of some of the claims, and lack of scientific support, all of which are quite justified (2).</description></item><item><title>Why Artificial Consciousness may be possible</title><link>https://rayes0.github.io/blog/consciousness/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rayes0.github.io/blog/consciousness/</guid><description>It is commonly accepted that machines cannot be conscious, and that any perceived consciousness is merely an imitation of organic consciousness. While I don&amp;rsquo;t disagree with these claims, there is not much solid proof for them, though of course, the same is true for the converse. However, it is still worth considering both sides of the problem. Therefore, for arguments sake, this article will lay out a series of examples and thought experiments potentially showing that artificial conscious could be possible.</description></item><item><title>*Hyouka*: My Thoughts</title><link>https://rayes0.github.io/blog/hyouka/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 16:45:09 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://rayes0.github.io/blog/hyouka/</guid><description>Meta-collection of loosely chronologically ordered miscellaneous thoughts on the Classic Literature Club light novel series by Honobu Yonezawa, compiled slowly bit by bit over many weeks as I reread all 6 volumes and rewatch all 22 episodes. The series showcases Oreki Houtarou, a high school boy and zealous energy conservationist. Starting with his first day of high school, it follows him as he experiences new situations challenging his previous way of life.</description></item></channel></rss>