<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>anemoia on rayes</title>
    <link>https://rayes0.github.io/anemoia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in anemoia on rayes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 21:49:34 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rayes0.github.io/anemoia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3</title>
      <link>https://rayes0.github.io/anemoia/chapter3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 21:49:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rayes0.github.io/anemoia/chapter3/</guid>
      <description>Evan rubbed his eyes. He was feeling slightly sleepy. It would probably be best to take a caffeine pill before he started his mission. Right now, Evan was in his dorm room. His roommate Philip seemed to have other things to do today. Maybe also an urgent mission? Evan didn&amp;rsquo;t know.
A few papers were propped up against his pillow. Next to them was a black file with the words &amp;lsquo;Grade A&amp;rsquo; written on the label.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2</title>
      <link>https://rayes0.github.io/anemoia/chapter2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 21:33:06 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rayes0.github.io/anemoia/chapter2/</guid>
      <description>There in the corner, encircled by shadows, was Headmaster Jules. He was a controlled man, who gave you the feeling that he was imperturbable. A former student at the school who, back in his day, was widely touted as the ideal version of a soldier. He was also rumoured to have been Nick&amp;rsquo;s teacher in his black suit days, and considered to have mastered the field of inferno magic. In other words, he was the best of the best.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1</title>
      <link>https://rayes0.github.io/anemoia/chapter1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 15:03:40 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rayes0.github.io/anemoia/chapter1/</guid>
      <description>(Twelve years after Prologue)
Evan awoke in his dorm room. He tried to open his eyes, but the morning sun filtering through the window was too much for him right now. Half squinting, he hauled himself out of the bed and proceeded to change into his blue suit. The dorms were nice and quiet at this time. Evan peered at another bed beside his, where his roommate Philip still lay sound asleep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prologue</title>
      <link>https://rayes0.github.io/anemoia/prologue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 21:42:35 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rayes0.github.io/anemoia/prologue/</guid>
      <description>It was a calm October day. The leaves were beginning to yellow. The air was damp but still clear, with a slight scent of morning dew still lingering. An open window let a constant, gentle breeze into the room, almost begging one to sit and daydream the day away. Time seemed to move in slow motion, like the lingering second before the last note of a beautiful piece of music.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
